Guide to the Gordon Bower papers SC1223
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-017
  - Childhood testimony of CSA, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Divided memories part 2, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Forgotten sins, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PBS: the forgetting documentary on alzheimer's, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Fatal memories Franklin, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - 3 faces of E., 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - TLC understanding the Mysteries of Memory, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - What Jennifer Saw, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - W/Gordon, 1991; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 10)
  - Capturing the Friedmans, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - A Journey into memory retrieval, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Walter Mischel interview with G. Bower, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Gordon Bower CEMS, 2014; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Bowerfest Banquet 2, 2005; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Candid camera, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Gordon Bower at Ventura Hall, 1992 Aug; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 10)
  - Slides for current use (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - unlabeled slides (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - unlabeled slides (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - unlabeled slides (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - unlabeled slides (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - 70th birthday celebration, 2003-2005 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence GB, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - G's retirement speech, 2004 November 13 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - correspondence, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - photos (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - math models, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Bower/ Gilligan SDR papers mood as context for learning remembering (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Report Bower, Efron win National Medal of Science, 2007 May 30 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Bower Days scrap book (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - American Institutes for Research Creative Talent Awards for Gordon H. Bower, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bush- medal of science, 2005-2006 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Kudos (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Kudos (2 of 2), 1980-2002 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notes to from Meehl, 1955 Jun 28 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cog sci banquet talk - final version, 1988 Aug (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - A history of psychology (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Formation of verbal schemata (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Demo materials (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Austria class, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - S, 1984-1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Yale papers, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Child memory: UT (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Seminar UT: emotion and memory (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Flashbulb M. class (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Day 1: introduction at Utexas, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Meeting #2: Utexas Jones Ch 1, 2: Bower Hist (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Bower's lecture notes on readings for seminars (various years) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Discussion Questions (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Syllabus psych 264 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Fest schrift (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - images (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - For conversation, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Mood congruence effects (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence with Phil, 2003 Fall (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Clippings (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Gordon Bower Fest Schrift photographs, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Vietnam - business cards (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - NIMH Grant proposal (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Articles reprints, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Gordon Bower's notebooks (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - papers (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photos, 2001-2010 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - papers (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - U of Iowa, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Funeral and Final Plans (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Omron blood pressure monitor pamphlet (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Stanford psych, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Adds., 2015 Apr 15 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - GB Memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - H+S Faculty Survey instrument follow up items (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 60th scio high school for Gordon B., 2010 Jun (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Banquet #1 Mischel, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - GB Memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Happy New Year 2013 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - monthly planner, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - GB Memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - GB Memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Photos GB (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Awards for distinguished scientific contributions, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Quad Lecture series, 1989 Oct 27 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Images (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - University of Chicago Convocation, 1991 Jun 14 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Clippings National medal of science, 2005-2007 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - National Medal of Science, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Yale memoirs, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - WPA '11 mentoring, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Retirement papers, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Papers (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Biographical notes, 2006 Apr (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Memorial service (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - 70th birthday party, 2002 November 22 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - correspondence, 1995 Feb (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Bowerfest, 2005 May 14 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Birthday photo (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Memoirs 9B, 1973-2004 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Memorabilia (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Robert Bower, 1945 Feb (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - other 9B pix in ecology file, 2009 Jul 6 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - G. Bower context episodic memory symposium, 2014 May 8-9 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Gordon - early photos news clippings (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - old photos re Bower clippings (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Current GB photos, 1990 Dec (Box 14, Folder 43)
- Restricted materials
  - Engel, Stephan (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Frosh: Grades, Evaluations, 2002 Fall (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - C-E recommendations, 1986-1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - A-B recommendations, 1980-2001 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - McDonald Fellowship Candidates, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations, 1978-2001 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Recommendations, 1979-2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations, 1982-2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Recommendations, 1986-2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Student materials (Box 16)